Venkata Krishnaiah Chiramana (1) Featured



Seeking roles in Software Development, Application Programming, Software Design, Agile Methodology, Cloud Computing, Project Management, Requirement Gathering, Google cloud computing(GCP), Airflow, AWS, Big data(Hadoop), Python, Linux, MySQL



Total Experience: 9 Year(s) 0 Month(s) Current Designation: Associate Architect

Current Company: Powerupcloud Technologies Notice Period: 1 Month

Current Location: Hyderabad / Secunderabad Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Electronics/Telecommunication] Pref. Location: Hyderabad

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: technical lead,software development,application programming,software design,agile methodology,project management,requirement gathering,putty,mysql,python,cloudera,linux,google cloud computing,AWS,Hadoop

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 20-Jan-21 Last Modified: 20-Jan-21

Summary

Having 9.5 years of IT experience in Development, Analysis, Design, Deployment, Reviewing, maintenance and integration of applications in entire software life cycle. Also having good experience in team handling as Technical lead. "Can-do" attitude and willingness to learn new emerging technologies and interested to take up new roles and responsibilities. Strong communication and interpersonal skills and a committed team player.

Work Experience

Powerupcloud Technologies as Associate Architect

Dec 2020 to Till Date

SEARS IT & MANAGEMENT SERVICES INDIA PVT as Technical Lead

Jul 2017 to Dec 2020

Project 4 Dynamic pricing (Migration from Hadoop to GCP)

Clients : Sears Holdings Corporation

Environment : GCP, Python, Hadoop, shell scripting, Git Hub, Airflow.

: MYSQL Databases Team Size : 6 : Technical Lead Role

Duration : July -2017 to Till Date

Description:

Sears Holdings Corporation is largest broad line retailer with over 4,000 full-line and specialty retail stores in the United States and Canada. Sears Holdings is the leading home appliance retailer as well as automotive repair and maintenance. Marketing & Pricing portfolio is one of key projects in organization, as the prices for Sears and Kmart items will be sent from this applications. The Store Pricing Application has been designed to generate Dynamic Pricing Recommendation for HA items. This can be later extended to other items. These recommendations are based on Rules created by Business users and data from different databases. This application contains main collision logic for price changes for a product. It also facilitates search for product at multiple levels.

Responsibilities:

- ? Understand Business Requirements.
- ? Do the analysis on the total existing batch flow and create design flow
- ? Run project tasks on Agile Sprint model to track the status and efforts to meet estimated timelines.
- ? Work with team to develop the application in GCP Cloud platform.
- ? Closely work with Client to complete Unit testing and Integration testing
- ? Parallel production by fixing the bugs.
- ? Production Deployment and maintenance

Sears Holdings as Senior Analyst

Sep 2014 to Jun 2017

Project 3 Pricing HUB (Migration from Hadoop to AWS)

Clients : Sears Holdings Corporation

Environment : AWS, Python, SVN, Hadoop, shell scripting, BMC Control-M.

Databases : MYSQL
Team Size : 5
Role : Senior analyst

Duration : Sept -2014 to June - 2017

Description:

Pricing Hub application is mainly used for product matching; Matching is very critical part with respect to pricing as we want to know how competitive we are in market and want to have ability for user to change prices based on competitor prices for the items that are not pricing by other system.

Responsibilities:

- * Understand Business Requirements.
- * Do the analysis on the total competitor and dynamic pricing batch flow and create design flow.
- * Work with SHI teams to develop the Hadoop process on AWS platform using Python Lambda functions & EC2 services.
- Closely work with Client to complete Unit testing and Integration testing
- * Parallel production by fixing the bugs on Hadoop platform.
- * Production Deployment and maintenance
- * Performs root cause analysis on production job failures and determines the work-around in possible ways, documents the analysis and work with developers and architects to develop a solution.

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Electronics/Telecommunication) from Anna University in 2009

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:

Google Cloud Platform Business Professional Accreditation

PYTHON FOR DATA SCIENCE

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
Linux/Unix, Windows.	
Python, Pig, Hive, SQoop, SQL	
Unix shell scripting	
Cloudera Hadoop Distribution (CDH5)	
Pycharm, Putty, Control-M, SVN	
FileZilla, MySQL workbenz	
MYSQLS	
GCP	

1/22/2021 https://freesearch.naukri.com/preview/printResume?uname=24ae0315ac2e07509cf626a3d3f4d6485b0c0a561c1701170413405f0e0...

AWS	0 0 Y	ear(s) 0 Month(s)
airflow		
airflow		

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
english	Proficient			

Affirmative Action

Category: General

Physically Challenged: No

Work Authorization

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time